JOSHUA SHANE EAGLE

Full Stack Developer HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript/Responsive/Adaptive Design/Mobile-First/MV*/Asynchronous Coding/JAVA/Nodes

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Specializing in Web Development, I have worked in the industry with a vast background of different technologies from the Backend, Frontend, and DEVOPS. All of these experiences has enabled me to understand what needs to be done not only for my work specifically, but for those who work in tandem together to achieve common goals. Additionally, my experience has empowered me to create powerful applications that adheres to the high standards of the industry, as well as cross-compatibility with multiple devices including mobile, all the way up to desktop.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer (Full-Stack)

Unisys Corporation, Fairfax, Virginia

August 2013 – September 2016

August 2013 – September 2016

Designing, architecting, pioneering and implementing the Next Generation of web applications for the United States Customs Border Protection. Where I have received high marks for out-of-box thinking improving the design and ease-of-use for each application.

Devices:.

Desktop Browsers: Chrome, Safari, Firefox, IE11+

Stack:

Node, Angular, Webpack, Java with Jersey, Junit, Jasmine, Selenium

Principal Consultant (Front-End Developer) Longview International Technology Solutions Inc., Fairfax, Virginia

Responsibilities include working in an agile environment, creating responsive, mobile-first web applications using Backbone/Marionette and Angular, executing 508-compliance, and phone-gap. My entire stay with Longview I worked on the Veteran Affairs Project.

- Maintained applications like Scheduling Manager, Veteran Appointment Requests as well as many other applications Frontend as well as the Backend. Fixing bugs, running Fortify Scans, and deploying the applications to Nexus preparing them for deployment. I have also worked on a DevOps team of three individuals in order to implement a Docker environment breaking new ground in a frontier that is in its infancy for the VA.
- Applications Developed: 8 (Telederm, Stroke-Pathway, Scheduling Manager, Veteran Appointment Request, Warfarin, Secure Messaging, Vitals, Labs, and Radiology). For Telederm, I worked with a backend developer to create the front-end bits of the application. For Stroke-Pathway, I implemented the Cordova components so that the

Web Experience

AJAX

Angular.js

Angular Material

Backbone.js

Bash

Bootstrap

CSS3

Docker

Drupal

Express

Grunt

Gulp

HTML5

Jade

Jasmine Unit Testing

JavaScript

JQuery

JSON

Lodash

Marionette.js

PHP

QUnit

Restful Services

Ruby

Selenium (web driver)

Webpack

Wordpress

Server Experience

Apache/Tomcat

IIS

Node.js

Ubuntu Server

Database Experience

MongoDB MySQL

Design Experience

Adobe

Photoshop

Illustrator

OS Experience

Chrome

Linux

Mac

Windows

Active Security Clearance:

Public Trust

application could run under Android as well as iOS. The rest of the applications I worked with a team of 6, (2 frontend, 3 backend, and 1 tester), I worked as a Front End developer using the technologies listed below in the Stack section.

Received high marks for Scheduling Manager as well as Veteran Appointment Request, which also got recognition from the 58th Speaker of the United States House of Representatives, Newt Gingrich.

Devices: All smart phones / tablets.

Desktop Browsers: Chrome, Safari, Firefox latest 4 versions, IE9/10+ (depending on app)

Stack:

Node, Angular, Backbone/Marionette, Handlebars, Underscore, Require, Modernizr, JQM, Twitter Bootstrap, Grunt.

Consultant (UX Developer)

April 2012 - August 2013

CGI Federal, Fairfax, Virginia

Responsibilities include working in an, agile environment, creating responsive web pages for government entities such as the Federally-Facilitated Exchange, and Centers for Medicare & Medicaid Services. My most recent work on the Federally-Facilitated Exchange has been presented at the White House for the new health care law that was passed under President Barack Hussein Obama.

Freelancer

January 2013 - April 2013

Lucinda Team, Annandale, Virginia

As a Freelancer, I was competing against 2 other companies, I was awarded the contract to develop a responsive website from Wordpress that the client could ultimately maintain. Responsibilities include designing a new look and feel, implementing Google Analytics for the use of Search Engine Optimization, and creating a responsive framework using HTML5, CSS3 and Javascript/jQuery.

Freelancer

October 2011 – April 2012

Navigant Consulting, Inc., Washington D.C.

Responsibilities include the development of bash scripting in the Linux environment, managing trouble tickets, and bug reports for the scripts. Trouble-shooting code, implements bug fixes, and maintaining the overall structure of the Linux environments for Navigant.

Associate (Developer)

June 2010 – February 2012

DRT Strategies Inc., Arlington, Virginia

Responsibilities include the development of Google Custom Search features, development with Drupal front and back-end, standing up and maintaining server infrastructure, creating mockups for websites using Photoshop, slicing those mockups into html/css themes which are cross-browser compatible, 508 compliant, and w3c validated. Maintaining database infrastructure, and supporting the IT infrastructure within DRT Strategies.

Project Summary

One West Bank: One West Bank tasked Navigant Consulting to lead compliance auditing of the

home foreclosure crisis that occurred from 2008 - 2009. As a subcontractor, I came up with the idea and was eventually tasked with the automation process for compiling thousands of loan documents through a complex process of converting .xlsx, .tif, .docx, .jpg, etc., into PDF format and merging them into one Master PDF file using Bash scripting in a Linux environment. Upon completion of the scripts needed for compilation, I managed the file transfers that included encrypting data with PGP in order to maintain the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the documents. Before I created this script, Navigant had a team of 6 individuals that would compile these files by hand that took many hours to complete a single batch that could have a hundred or more loan documents and each loan document could have many different file types, whereas my script could compile their entire stack in an 30 minutes or less, saving thousands of dollars in man-hours that were moved to other tasks.

Equal Before Law: The Eurasia Foundation needed a Drupal website that would provide the people of Eurasia with pertinent information of an individual's rights before the law. Responsibilities included the standing up of an Amazon (EC2) Linux server that would support the implementation of Drupal with MySQL, the theming of Drupal, as well as the development of features required by the client, including the creation of custom modules written in PHP as well as the implementation of SOLR search powered by Apache.

Sba.gov: This project involved the website redesign for the Small Business Administration. Using Drupal as the content management system and MySQL as the database system, I was able to successfully redesign SBA's website with outstanding marks. Responsibilities include managing a \$2.5 million server system, develop and theme the Drupal environment, creating custom PHP written modules that use hook_form_alter() functions to make use of the Google Custom Search features, and push updates from the development servers to the production servers. I have received recognition as well as a merit bonus for my commitment to its success and stability.

EDUCATION

B.S., Information Technology George Mason University

Minor: Business
Dean's List

January 2007 - May 2010